Hi everyone!
안녕하세요 여러분!
My name is Kirill.
제 이름은 키릴입니다.
My name is Darina.
제 이름은 다리나입니다.
Today we came to the Socio-Pedagogical Institute.
오늘 저희는 사회교육학 대학에 왔습니다.
We wanted to learn more about it, get to know it,
저희는 이곳에 대해 더 많이 알고, 직접 경험해 보고 싶었습니다.
learn more about the teachers and get acquainted with the students here.
교수님들을 더 잘 알아보고 이곳 학생들과 친해지고 싶었습니다.
And I still don't know where I'm going to apply or what profession
저는 아직 어디에 지원할지, 어떤 전공을 선택할지 모르겠어요.
I didn't know that either back in my time.
저도 그 당시엔 몰랐어요.
But my friend helped me with that — he inspired me,
하지만 제 친구가 도움을 줬어요, 그 친구가 저에게 영감을 줬거든요,
told me what to do and where to go.
어디로 가야 할지를요.
And now let me give you a mini-tour of this institute.
자, 이제 이 대학에 대한 미니 투어를 시작해 볼게요.
So, did Kirill learn it?
자, 외웠어요 키릴?
Yes.
네.
So far we like everything,
지금까지는 다 마음에 들어요,
it's a bit confusing with so many corridors.
복도가 너무 많아서 좀 복잡하네요.
because my life is going to be wonderful.
왜냐하면 제 삶이 멋질 거니까요.
And we've been here before — we had career guidance here
저희 여기 왔었어요, 직업 오리엔테이션이 있었거든요.
Oh, not bad
오, 좋네요.
We had a competition here, we came last place.
저희 대회가 있었는데, 꼴찌를 했어요.
Here, really?
어디서요, 여기서요?
Yes.
네.
Well, this is the Assembly Hall.
자, 이곳이 강당입니다.
Lectures are held here, and here is a special stand.
강의가 진행되고, 여기 전용 단상이 있습니다.
What is it called? Does anyone know?
이게 뭐라고 부르나요? 아는 분 있나요?
A podium. (the operator said)
연단이요. (촬영기사가 말했다)
What?
네?
Who knows?
아는 분 있나요?
A podium. (overheard the operator's answer)
연단이요. (촬영기사의 대답을 엿들었다)
Where should I sit? Kirill, come on, organize it!
어디 있으면 될까요? 키릴, 좀 정리해 줘요!
Well, sit here.
여기 앉으세요.
Everything is fine.
다 좋아요.
Guys, we decided to interview a student
여러분, 저희가 학생 한 명과 인터뷰를 하기로 했습니다.
of the Socio-Pedagogical Institute — Pasha.
사회교육학 대학의 학생 파샤입니다.
Hi, my name is Pasha.
안녕하세요, 제 이름은 파샤입니다.
As you already know, I'm studying in my second year in the program
아시다시피, 저는 2학년으로 전공 방향은
Pedagogical Education with two majors in Biology and Chemistry, already in second year.
생물학과 화학 두 가지 전공 과정을 가진 교육학, 2학년에 재학 중입니다.
I expressed my desire to enter our Socio-Pedagogical Institute
저는 우리 사회교육학 대학에 입학하고 싶다는 의지를 표명했습니다.
while still studying in 11th grade.
이미 11학년에 재학 중일 때요.
I had a goal, and I achieved it.
목표가 있었고, 그 목표를 이뤘습니다.
I passed the EGE (the Russian national school-leaving exam after 11th grade) quite well and enrolled.
ЕГЭ(러시아 11학년 졸업시험)를 꽤 좋은 점수로 합격하고 입학했습니다.
And what profession do you want to go into afterwards?
나중에 어떤 직업을 갖고 싶으세요?
I haven't really thought about it yet — I'll keep studying and getting my education.
아직 그런 생각을 해보지 않았어요, 계속 공부하면서 교육을 받을 거예요.
Why did you decide to leave after 11th grade and not after 9th grade?
9학년이 아닌 11학년 이후에 떠나기로 한 이유가 뭔가요?
In my opinion it was easier to enroll and less time is spent that way.
제 생각엔 그게 더 쉽고 시간이 덜 걸리는 방법이었어요.
That's all.
이상이에요.
Wait, after 11th grade? (operator)
그러니까, 11학년 이후에요? (촬영기사)
Yes.
네.
How so? (operator)
어떻게요? (촬영기사)
Why less time? (operator)
왜 시간이 덜 걸리나요? (촬영기사)
Less time, because college takes more time.
시간이 덜 걸리는 이유는 칼리지에서 더 많은 시간이 소요되기 때문이에요.
Really? (operator)
그래요? (촬영기사)
Yes, two extra years.
네, 2년이 더요.
So it turns out that if someone left after 9th grade, from among my peers, so to speak,
그러면 제 동료들, 말하자면, 9학년 이후에 떠난 사람들은
they are already...
그들은 이미...
They are still studying at college
그들은 아직 칼리지에서 공부 중이에요.
Or possibly already finished.
이미 졸업했을 수도 있죠.
And this year they graduate and only then enroll in the first year
올해 졸업하고 나서야 1학년으로 입학하는 거죠.
of higher education.
고등 교육으로요.
Let's imagine you're already a teacher. (operator)
당신이 이미 선생님이라고 가정해 봐요. (촬영기사)
So, the EGE — what ones are you planning to give.
자, ЕГЭ(러시아 11학년 졸업시험), 어떤 과목을 가르칠 예정인가요.
Are you going to give EGE exams at all?
ЕГЭ(러시아 11학년 졸업시험)를 실제로 가르칠 건가요?
What's on your plan?
계획은 어떻게 되나요?
When I finish 11th grade
11학년을 마칠 때
Go on
그래요.
Social Studies, History, English
사회, 역사, 영어를
I'll be taking 5 exams.
5과목을 응시할 거예요.
A lot, a lot.
많이도, 많이도.
Are you ready at all?
준비됐어요?
Well, it's in progress
음, 준비 중이에요.
Well, I'm ready for the OGE (the Russian national exam after 9th grade)
ОГЭ(러시아 9학년 졸업시험)는 준비됐어요.
For now you need to pass the OGE, right?
우선 ОГЭ(러시아 9학년 졸업시험)를 봐야죠?
Yes.
네.
Well, that's easy, not hard.
그건 쉬워요, 어렵지 않아요.
Pasha, can you give some advice on passing the EGE? (operator)
파샤, ЕГЭ(러시아 11학년 졸업시험) 응시에 대한 조언 해줄 수 있어요? (촬영기사)
Because a lot of people are scared of the EGE. (operator)
왜냐하면 많은 사람들이 ЕГЭ(러시아 11학년 졸업시험)를 무서워하거든요. (촬영기사)
EGE, EGE, EGE — there's no need to be afraid
ЕГЭ, ЕГЭ, ЕГЭ, 무서워할 필요 없어요.
It's all quite systematic.
체계적으로 되어 있거든요.
Every day, even just a little, do practice variants.
매일 조금씩이라도 문제를 풀어보세요.
You'll notice they're roughly the same.
패턴을 외우게 될 거예요, 문제들이 비슷하거든요.
You'll build up, gain knowledge, gain experience, and then
실력을 쌓고, 지식과 경험을 얻게 돼요.
you'll pass that exam with confidence.
그러면 자신 있게 시험에 합격할 수 있어요.
Alright, shall we let our dear guest go. (operator)
자, 이제 우리 소중한 손님을 보내드릴까요. (촬영기사)
Yes, thank you very much.
네, 정말 감사합니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Well, our video is coming to an end.
자, 저희 영상이 마무리되어 가고 있습니다.
I am very glad that the guys came to us.
여러분이 와주셔서 정말 기쁩니다.
I'm very pleased that they walked around, had a look, met the teachers and the students.
여러분이 둘러보고, 교수님들과 학생들을 만나보셨다니 정말 즐거웠습니다.
So, what can be said?
자, 무슨 말을 할 수 있을까요?
That, guys, there is a whole life ahead, a whole journey, a whole road.
여러분, 앞으로 인생 전체, 여정 전체, 길 전체가 펼쳐져 있습니다.
And it's important to make the right decision at the right time.
제때 올바른 결정을 내리는 것이 중요합니다.
So use your head, be smart, be kind and well-mannered
그러니 머리를 잘 쓰고, 영리하게, 친절하고 예의 바르게 생활하세요.
And everything will be fine.
그러면 다 잘 될 거예요.
That's it.
네.
Goodbye everyone.
모두 안녕히 계세요.
Subscribe to Sotsium, subscribe to our group Prodolzheniye (Continuation).
소치움을 구독하고, 저희 그룹 프로돌제니에를 구독해 주세요.
When we were all studying together, we had Media and Advertising classes.
저희가 함께 공부할 때, 미디어와 광고 수업이 있었습니다.
As a practice project we decided to shoot this full-length video.
실습으로 이렇게 큰 영상을 만들기로 했습니다.
So be sure to subscribe and follow us.
그러니 꼭 구독하고 저희를 팔로우해 주세요.
We will continue to do something big and beautiful.
앞으로도 크고 멋진 콘텐츠를 만들어 나갈게요.
Alright, bye.
이상입니다, 안녕히 계세요.